Mello, Michael; Papers apap287
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Michael Mello Papers
1800-2008
1970-2004
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Mello, Michael
apap287
42.2 cubic ft.
Michael A. Mello (1957-2008) was an internationally recognized authority on the death penalty and capital punishment issues. He was a lawyer, professor, and author. Michael Mello served as counsel or informal advisor to many significant cases, including Joseph Robert Crazy Joe Spaziano, Theodore Kaczynski, Theodore Bundy, Rolando Cruz, Alvin Ford, Stephen Todd Booker, and Robert Straight.
Biographical History
Michael A. Mello (1957-2008) was an internationally recognized authority on the death penalty and capital punishment issues. He graduated from the University of Virginia, School of Law in 1982. From 1982-1983, he worked as a law clerk for Judge Robert S. Vance of the United States Court of Appeals for the Eleventh District where his principal responsibility included working on many of the capital cases for which the judge was assigned. From 1983-1985, he worked as an assistant public defender for the Capital Appeals Division of the Office of the Flordia Public Defender where he was lead cousel in three capital cases and active co-counsel in ten others as well as providing tactical and strategic assistance to pro bono attorneys, developing systemic strategies, lobbying, and testifying before the Florida Legislature. From 1985-1986, Mello worked for the Office of the Capital Collateral Representative for the State of Florida, a first-of-its-kind state agency charged with representing all indigient inmantes on Florida's death row whose sentences had been affirmed by the Florida Supreme Court and who had been denied executive clemency by the governor. Though he left his position at the Capital Collateral Respresentative in 1986, he remained on friendly terms with the organization where he provided advice and took the occasional case until 1995 when he cut off ties with the organization. From 1988 until his death in November 2008, Michael Mello was a professor of law at Vermont Law School where he taught courses on criminal law, constitutional criminal procedure, the legal profession, and a capital punishment seminar.
Michael Mello served as counsel or informal advisor to many significant cases, including Joseph Robert Crazy Joe Spaziano, Theodore Kaczynski, Theodore Bundy, Rolando Cruz, Alvin Ford, Stephen Todd Booker, and Robert Straight. He also served as counsel for the American Bar Association, National Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers, National Legal Aid and Defender Association, American Jewish Congress, American Jewish Committee, and others.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes material related to some of Michael Mello's more significant cases; including Joseph Crazy Joe Spaziano, Davidson James, Bennie Demps, and Nollie Lee Martin. Also included are drafts and complete copies of a number of Michael Mellos publications, research files used by Michael Mello in the various aspects of his professional life, case files for which Michael Mello may have been involved in some capacity. The majority of the material involves Michael Mello's professional life from the mid-1980s to the late 1990s.
Researchers should note that materials related to some of Michael Mello's most significant cases such as Theodore Bundy and Theodore Kaczynski is not included in this collection.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into eight topical series.
Acquisition Information
Michael Mello and his wife Deanna donated these records to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives in a series of three acquisitions in 2006, 2012, and 2013.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Death Penalty; Death row inmates--Florida; Capital punishment--United States; Capital punishment--Florida; Legal research and writing; Death Penalty; Capital punishment--United States--Cases; Executions (Law)--United States--Cases; Capital punishment--Moral and ethical aspects; Legislative acts; Legal documents; Decisions; Drafts (documents); Correspondence; Manuscripts (document genre); Case files; Books; Mello, Michael; Spaziano, Joseph; James, Davidson; Martin, Nollie Lee; Demps, Bennie
- Joseph Spaziano, 1932-2008; 1; 7.6 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains materials related to the various trials of Joseph Spaziano and represents material created or used by Michael Mello in Joseph Spazianos defense or during the writing of Michael Mellos book The Wrong Man: A True Story of Innocence and the Death Row; included in this series are legal materials, correspondence, notes, and research materials.
  - Research Materials Hypnosis Articles, 1932-1969 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 1)
  - Research Material- Criminal Justice Act of 1963 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 2)
  - Research Materials- Scope of Gardner Issue, 1958; 1984-1985 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 3)
  - Research Materials- Jury Override (1 of 2), 1966-1984 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 4)
  - Research Materials- Jury Override (2 of 2), 1966 -1984 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 5)
  - Research Materials- Hypnosis Cases, 1968; 1971; 1974-1984 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 6)
  - Research Materials- Per Se Exclusion, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 7)
  - Interview- Anthony Frank Dilisio, 1975 May 15 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 8)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - 9th Circuit FL, Trial Proceedings Volume II, 1975 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 9)
  - Research Material- Alford v. State, 1975; 1977; 1979 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 10)
  - Chronological Testimony of Athony Frank Dilisio, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 11)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (1 of 9), 1975- 1995 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 12)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist to view material
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (2 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 13)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (3 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 14)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (4 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 15)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (5 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 16)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (6 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 17)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (7 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 18)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (8 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 19)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (9 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 20)
  - UCI Medical File, [Restricted] (1 of 2), 1975-1995 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 21)
  - UCI Medical File, [Restricted] (2 of 2), 1975-1995 (Box 1 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 22)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. I, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 1)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. II, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 2)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. III, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 3)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - upreme Court of Florida- Vol. IV, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 4)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. V, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 5)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. VI, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 6)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. VII, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 7)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida (1 of 3), 1976-1984 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 8)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida (2 of 3), 1976-1984 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 9)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida (3 of 3), 1976-1984 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 10)
  - Research Materials, 1978 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 11)
  - Unknown Argument, 1978 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 12)
  - Research Material, Allen Charge, 1978-1985 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 13)
  - Reference Material, 1980 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 14)
  - Research Materials- Gerald Eugene Stano, 1980-1983 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 15)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 18th Century, FL- Imposition of Sentence after Remand, 1981 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 16)
  - Presentation Investigaton, 1981 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 17)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of FL. - Record on Resentencing Vol. I, 1981 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 18)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of FL. - Record on Resentencing Vol. II, 1981 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 19)
  - News Reports, 1981; 1984-1986; 1989-1991; 1995 (Box 2 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 20)
  - Spaziano Cases in Southern Reporter, 1983; 1986; 1989-1990 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 1)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - U.S SC (1 of 2), 1981-1984 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 2)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - U.S SC (2 of 2), 1981-1984 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 3)
  - Gardner Resentencing - Diskette, 1981-1984; Undated (Oversized 1, Item 4)
  - Gardener Resentencing, 1981-1984; Undated (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 4)
  - Research Materials, 1982 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 5)
  - Research Materials, Habeas Corpus, 1982; 1984-1985 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 7)
  - Research Material, 1983 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 8)
  - Clemency- Investigative Materials, 1984 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 10)
  - Reference Materials, 1984 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 11)
  - Notes, 1984-1985; Undated (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 12)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency in RE: Joseph R. Spaziano- In Support of Executive Clemency, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 13)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency in RE: Joseph R. Spaziano- In Support, Appendix, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 14)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency in RE: Joseph R. Spaziano- Supplemental Memorandum, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 15)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency in RE: Joseph R. Spaziano- Supplemental Memorandum In Support of Executive Clemency, Appendix, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 17)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- 18th Circuit, FL. (1 of 2), 1985 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 18)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- 18th Circuit, FL. (2 of 2), 1985 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 19)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- 18th Circuit, FL., Motion to Vacate Judgement and Sentence, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 20)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- 18th Circuit, FL., Motion to Vacate Judgement and Sentence, Appendix Vol. I of III, (1 of 2), 1985 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 21)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- 18th Circuit, FL., Motion to Vacate Judgement and Sentence, Appendix Vol. I of III, (2 of 2), 1985 (Box 3 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 22)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- Eighteenth Circuit- Rule 3.850- Motion to Vacate Judgement and Sentence, Appendix II, 1985 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 1)
  - Spaziano v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit, 1990-1991 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 2)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 9th Circuit FL, 1990-1991 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 3)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Record on Appeal, Vol. II, 1990 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 4)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Appeal, Vol. I, 1990 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 5)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FL. SC, 1990 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 6)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - U.S. D.C. FL., 1990 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 7)
  - Research Materials, 1990 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 9)
  - Spaziano v. Dugger - FLSC- Record on Appeal, 1989-1990 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 10)
  - Spaziano v. Dugger - USDL, FL, 1989 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 11)
  - Spaziano v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit, 1989 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 12)
  - Spaziano Federal Habeas- Index of Claims - Computer Contents, 1989 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 13)
  - Research Materials, 1989 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 14)
  - Newsclippings, 1989 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 16)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Record on Appeal (2 of 2), 1988-1989 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 17)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Record on Appeal (1 of 2), 1988-1989 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 18)
  - Research Materials, 1988 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 19)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court FL., 1987 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 20)
  - Research Material, 1987 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 21)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Record on Appeal, 1986-1989 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 22)
  - Spaziano v. Wainwright - U.S.S.L, 1986 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 23)
  - Spaziano v. Wainwright- FLSC, 1986 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 24)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - USSC, 1986 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 25)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC, 1986 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 26)
  - Research Materials, 1986 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 4 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 28)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC, 1985 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 1)
  - Death Warrant, 1985 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 2)
  - Research Material, 1985 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 3)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 18th Circuit FL- Motion to Vacate Judgement and Sentence Appendix Vol.III of III, ca. 1985 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 4)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary -US DC FL, 1990-1991 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 6)
  - Research Materials, 1991 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 8)
  - Spaziano v. Dugger - FL Sc, 1992 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 9)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - USDC, FL ( 1 of 2), 1992 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 10)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - USDC, FL ( 2 of 2), 1992 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 11)
  - Research Materials, 1992 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 12)
  - Research Material - Franklin v. Duncan (1 of 3), 1992 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 13)
  - Research Material - Franklin v. Duncan (2 of 3), 1992 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 14)
  - Research Material - Franklin v. Duncan (3 of 3), 1992 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 15)
  - Research Materials- Repressed Memories ( 1 of 2), 1992-1995; Undated (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 16)
  - Research Materials- Repressed Memories ( 2 of 2), 1992-1995; Undated (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 18)
  - Radelet Affidavit, 1993 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 19)
  - Radelet and Bedau Affidavit, 1993 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 20)
  - Research Materials, 1993 (Box 5 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 21)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit- Record Experts ( 1 of 4), 1993 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 1)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit- Record Experts ( 2 of 4), 1993 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 2)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit- Record Experts ( 3 of 4), 1993 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 3)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit- Record Experts ( 4 of 4), 1993 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 4)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit ( 1 of 2), 1993 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 5)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit ( 2 of 2), 1993 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 6)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary -U.S. D.C. FL., 1993 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 7)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - Summary of Time Spent by Appointed Counsel, 1993-1994 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 9)
  - Research Materials, 1994 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 10)
  - Research Materials - False Memory Syndrome Foundation, 1994-1995 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 11)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US SC- Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the United States Court of Appeals for the Eleventh Circuit, 1994 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 12)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US SC- Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the United States Court of Appeals for the Eleventh Circuit, Appendices ( 1 of 2), 1994 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 13)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US SC- Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the United States Court of Appeals for the Eleventh Circuit, Appendices ( 2 of 2), 1994 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 14)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US SC- Respondents Brief in Opposition to Writ of Ceritorari ( 1 of 2), 1994 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 15)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - Respondents Brief in Opposition to Writ of Ceritorari ( 2 of 2), 1994 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 16)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA 11th Circuit, 1994-1995 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 17)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US SC, 1994-1995 (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 18)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 April (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 19)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 June (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 20)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 June (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 21)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 July (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 22)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 August (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 23)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 September (Box 6 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 24)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 October (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 1)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 November (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 December (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 3)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency- Application, 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 4)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency- Supplemental Appendix, 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 5)
  - Before the Governor and the Board of Executive Clemency, 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 6)
  - Correspondence ( 1 of 3), 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 7)
  - Correspondence ( 2 of 3), 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence ( 3 of 3), 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 9)
  - Information Packet- " The Hypnotized Witness and the Condemned Man: The Joseph ( "Crazy Joe") Spaziano Case", 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 10)
  - Interview- Anthony Frank Dilisio, 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 11)
  - Research Materials, 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 12)
  - Death Warrant, 1995 May (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 13)
  - Spaziano Execution Alert, 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 14)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FL SC (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 15)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FL SC (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 16)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FL SL, 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 17)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Request to Enforce Rights, 1995 (Box 7 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 18)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - USSL, 1995 (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 1)
  - Statement to Governor Lawton Chiles in a Support of a New Trial, 1995 (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 January (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 3)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 February (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 4)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 March (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 5)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 April (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 6)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 August (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 7)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 December (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 9)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 9th Circuit, FL. (1 of 2), 1996 (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 10)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 9th Circuit, FL. (2 of 2), 1996 (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 11)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 18th Circuit FL., 1996 (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 12)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - FLSL, 1996 (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 8 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 14)
  - Plea Bargain, 1998 (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2008 (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 4)
  - Draft Application for Story of Execution, Undated (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 5)
  - Newsclippings, Undated (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 6)
  - Notes, Undated (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 7)
  - Research Materials, Undated (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 8)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Draft Supplement to Rehearing Motions, Undated (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 9)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Draft Amendment to Previously Filed Rehearing Motions, Undated (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 10)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Trial Transcript, Undated (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 11)
  - Unlabeled Skeletal Photographs, Undated (Box 9 (1-Joseph Spaziano), Folder 12)
- Davidson James, 1970-1993; 2; 2.2 cubic ft.
  This series contains legal material, notes, research files, and correspondence related to the trials of Davidson James.
  - Notes and Research, 1970; 1976; 1979; 1982-1993; Undated (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 1)
  - Notes and Research, 1970; 1976; 1979; 1982-1993; Undated (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 2)
  - James v. Florida- FLSC, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 3)
  - Florida v. James- 13th Circuit, FL, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 4)
  - Florida v. James- 13th Circuit, FL ( 1 of 2), 1986 (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 5)
  - Florida v. James- 13th Circuit, FL ( 2 of 2), 1986 (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 6)
  - James v. Wainwright- USSC, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 7)
  - James v. Wainwright- Middle District of FL, Tampa Division ( 1 of 2), 1986 (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 8)
  - James v. Wainwright- Middle District of FL, Tampa Division ( 2 of 2), 1986 (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 9)
  - James v. Wainwright- USDC, M. FL, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 10)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit ( 1 of 3), 1987 (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 11)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit ( 2 of 3), 1987 (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 12)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit ( 3 of 3), 1987 (Box 1 (2-Davidson James), Folder 13)
  - James v. Wainwright - FLSC ( 1 of 3), ca. 1987 (Box 2 (2-Davidson James), Folder 1)
  - James v. Wainwright - FLSC ( 2 of 3), ca. 1987 (Box 2 (2-Davidson James), Folder 2)
  - James v. Wainwright - FLSC ( 2 of 3), ca. 1987 (Box 2 (2-Davidson James), Folder 3)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA 11th Circuit ( 1 of 2), 1988 (Box 3 (2-Davidson James), Folder 1)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA 11th Circuit ( 2 of 2), 1988 (Box 3 (2-Davidson James), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Re. James, 1988-1990; 1992-1993; Undated (Box 3 (2-Davidson James), Folder 3)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA 11th Circuit, 1989-1990 (Box 3 (2-Davidson James), Folder 4)
  - James v. Florida - FLSC, 1992 (Box 3 (2-Davidson James), Folder 5)
  - James v. Singletary - USCA, 11th Circuit, 1992 (Box 3 (2-Davidson James), Folder 6)
  - James v. Wainwright - USDC, M. FL, 1992 (Box 3 (2-Davidson James), Folder 7)
  - James v. Singletary - USDC, M. FL, 1992-1993 (Box 4 (2-Davidson James), Folder 1)